Guide to the Arthur F. Burns Papers, 1911-2005 and undated, bulk 1940-1987 RL.00179
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1911-1997 and undated, bulk 1940-1987, 5 boxes; 347 electronic files
  - Correspondence by Individual, 1911-1985, bulk 1953-1981
    - Richard Milhous Nixon, 1955-1980, 12 folders
      - From Nixon to Burns, 1957-1980, 92 letters
        - 1957 Jan. 14 (Box 2)
        - 1958 June 17 (Box 2)
          Re: Anti-Recession plan. Attached: 2 items. Letters from J. T. Moll to Nixon, 1958 May 15 and 1958 Apr. 2, both with carbon copies.
        - 1958 Sept. 10 (Box 2)
        - 1958 Oct. 25 (Box 2)
        - 1958 Dec. 15 (Box 2)
        - 1959 Oct. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1960 Apr. 18 (Box 2)
        - 1960 Apr. 26 (Box 2)
        - 1960 June 3 (Box 2)
        - 1960 June 8 (Box 2)
        - 1960 Aug. 15 (Box 2)
        - 1960 Aug. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1960 Aug. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1960 Sept. 9 (Box 2)
        - 1960 Sept. 25 (Box 2)
        - 1961 Jan. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1961 Apr. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1961 June 7 (Box 2)
          Re: Burns's critique of the administration's economic policies
        - 1961 June 8 (Box 2)
        - 1961 June 30 (Box 2)
        - 1961 Aug. 21 (Box 2)
          Re: Nixon's decision about whether or not to run for governor of California.
        - 1961 Sept. 11 (Box 2)
        - 1961 Nov. 8 (Box 2)
        - 1962 Jan. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1962 Aug. 27 (Box 2)
        - 1963 Feb. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1963 May 14 (Box 2)
        - 1967 Dec. 5 (Box 2)
        - 1968 Aug. 29 (Box 2)
        - 1968 Dec. 2 (Box 2)
          Re: Nixon's request for Burns to make recommendations about individuals to be recruited by the new administration.
        - 1969 Apr. 27 (Box 2)
        - 1969 May 7 (Box 2)
          From Burns to Nixon expressing concern about the "official family" (some members of Staff and the Cabinet) and how harmful their leaking of stories to the media is to the Nixon administration. First page has Nixon's handwritten response at top.
        - 1969 Sept. 9 (Box 2)
          From Pat Nixon to Burns.
        - 1969 Nov. 15 (Box 2)
          Telegram to Thomas M. Macioce. Re: Presentation of Alexander Hamilton Medal to Burns.
        - 1969 Nov. 20 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Jan. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Feb. 18 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Apr. 23 (Box 2)
        - 1970 May 19 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Aug. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Sept. 23 (Box 2)
          Attached: News clipping, The New York Times, 1970 Sept. 22.
        - 1970 Nov. 29 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Nov. 29 (Box 2)
          From Nixon to Pepperdine College, honoring Burns.
        - 1970 Dec. 5 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 2 (Box 2)
          Memorandum for Connally, Burns, Shultz, McCracken, Peterson, and Flanigan. Nixon underlines that he does not want anymore speculation and leaks to public regarding important economic matters from the White House Staff. Formerly classified as SECRET and declassified by ISOO, 2015.
        - 1971 Nov. 4 (Box 2)
          [EYES ONLY] Nixon's concerns about the political implications of the tight monetary policy of the FED. Nixon calls on Burns to review this policy.
        - 1972 Jan. 28 (Box 2)
          [EYES ONLY] Nixon's admonishing message concerning Burns's/FED's promise about the money supply. The letter has a handwritten note by Burns.
        - 1972 May 4 (Box 2)
          Re: Burns's support concerning measures against North Vietnamese invasion of South Vietnam.
        - 1972 June 8 (Box 2)
          Re: Nixon's visit to Moscow and enduring peace between USA and USSR
        - 1972 June 27 (Box 2)
        - 1972 June 30 (Box 2)
          Re: Burns's memorandum on price policy.
        - 1972 Sept 6 (Box 2)
        - 1972 Sept. 21 (Box 2)
        - 1972 Sept. 22 (Box 2)
          Re: Latin American affairs.
        - 1972 Nov. 27 (Box 2)
          Re: Election victory.
        - 1972 Dec. 15 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Jan. 5 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Feb. 14 (Box 2)
          Re: Phase III of the Economic Stabilization Program and the Nixon Administration's determination to enforce the program and relevant price and wage control measures
        - 1973 June 4 (Box 2)
        - 1973 June 13 (Box 2)
        - 1973 July 23 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Aug. 9 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Aug. 23 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Sept. 12 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Sept. 18 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Oct. 25 (Box 2)
        - 1973 Dec. 12 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Feb. 13 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Mar. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1974 Apr. 11 (Box 2)
        - 1974 May 31 (Box 2)
          Re: Economic Stabilization Program.
        - 1974 June 3 (Box 2)
        - 1974 June 9 (Box 2)
          Re: Burns's visit to USSR.
        - 1974 Dec. 27 (Box 2)
        - 1975 Aug. 4 (Box 2)
        - 1977 Jan. 19 (Box 2)
        - 1980 July 7 (Box 2)
        - 1981 Dec. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1982 July 21 (Box 2)
        - 1983 July 11 (Box 2)
          Nixon to Helmut Kohl
        - 1983 Sept. 9 (Box 2)
        - 1983 July 22 (Box 2)
        - 1983 Oct. 10 (Box 2)
        - 1984 Apr. 24 (Box 2)
        - 1984 May 4 (Box 2)
          Nixon's secretary to Burns
        - 1985 May 29 (Box 2)
        - 1985 July 24 (Box 2)
        - 1986 Feb. 14 (Box 2)
        - 1986 June 23 (Box 2)
      - From Burns to Nixon, 1955, 1970-1974, 122 letters
        The correspondence from Arthur Frank Burns to Nixon covers the period during which Dr. Burns acted as the Chairman of the Federal Reserve and is comprised of letters and memoranda sent to the president. Major issues addressed in the correspondence are economic measures to be taken in order to fight inflation and recession, the monetary policy that the Federal Reserve should pursue in accordance with the Economic Stabilization Act, the issue of wage and price controls, the gold crisis, the value of the dollar, and policies that the administration should implement concerning the international monetary situation.
        The letters provide important insights into the disagreements between the Nixon Administration and Chairman Burns with regards to the issues of money supply, the extent and strictness of wage and price controls, and international monetary policy. The letters also address political matters such as Burns' opinions about domestic politics, his complaints about some White House staff, and the Watergate Scandal. International economic and political matters such as the Vietnam War, the policy of détente with the Soviet Union, and US relations with Latin American countries are also mentioned in the correspondence. Burns's handwritten journals, 1969-1974, found in the Journals Series in this collection, compliment this set of correspondence.
        - 1955 June 29 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Feb. 2 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Feb. 2 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Feb. 6 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Feb. 11 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Feb. 19 (Box 2)
          Attached: How the Federal Reserve System Affects the Money Supply.
        - 1970 Mar. 9 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Mar. 17 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Apr. 8 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Apr. 24 (Box 2)
        - 1970 May 15 (Box 2)
        - 1970 May 17 (Box 2)
        - 1970 June 23 (Box 2)
        - 1970 June 23 (Box 2)
        - 1970 July 1 (Box 2)
        - 1970 July 3 (Box 2)
        - 1970 July 24 (Box 2)
        - 1970 July 24 (Box 2)
        - 1970 July 31 (Box 2)
          Attached: Report, Import Shares in Nonfood Goods and the Cut-Back in Defense Expenditures, prepared by Clayton Gehman, 1970 July 22.
        - 1970 Aug. 28 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Sept. 16 (Box 2)
          Re: Refusal to join Nixon for his visit to Heath in London
        - 1970 Oct. 15 (Box 2)
          Re: The tragic impact of "irresponsible trade unions" on the construction industry in Kansas City.
        - 1970 Dec. 5 (Box 2)
        - 1970 Dec. 9 (Box 2)
          Attached: News clipping about the Fed's anti-inflation measures and Burns' comments on Nixon's statement reassuring "adequate money supply" in the market.
        - 1970 Dec. 21 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Jan. 16 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Jan. 18 (Box 2)
          Attached: Memorandum from Geoffrey H. Moore, Commissioner of Labor Statistics regarding estimated impact of labor compensation increase on unemployment, 1971 Jan. 15.
        - 1971 Feb. 10 (Box 2)
          Re: Secretary of Treasury, John Connally.
        - 1971 Feb. 18 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Feb. 20 (Box 2)
          Re: Rowen Bart's story about his testimony in The Washington Post. Burns also complains about "well-meaning" but "ill-advised" public talks by White House officials whose statements are presented as indications of a conflict around the monetary policy between Burns and Nixon.
        - 1971 Feb. 26 (Box 2)
          Re: Suspension of the David-Bacon Act.
        - 1971 Mar. 10 (Box 2)
        - 1971 May 19 (Box 2)
          [STRICTLY CONFIDENTIAL] Burns's comments on the ongoing international crisis, suggesting that if the US has to suspend gold sales and purchases, it make it appear as if the US government was forced to do so by other governments' actions; otherwise, he argues, the US would have a weaker bargaining position in post-suspension negotiations. He also advises the government to "pay out gold and other reserves in substantial amounts," before a suspension.
        - 1971 May 19 (Box 2)
        - 1971 May 28 (Box 2)
        - 1972 June 10 (Box 2)
        - 1971 June 22 (Box 2)
          Re: Opinion that the fiscal and monetary policies of the government were not as effective as expected.
        - 1971 June 30 (Box 2)
        - 1971 July 22 (Box 2)
          Re: China-US relations.
        - 1971 July 22 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Aug. 4 (Box 2)
          Re: Suggestion that the differences between us on matters of economic policy are really minor..
        - 1971 Aug. 5 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Sept. 8 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Sept. 10 (Box 2)
          Burns's notes on meeting with the President and labor groups.
        - 1971 Sept. 21 (Box 2)
          Memorandum for the President, in which Burns details his suggestions to Nixon regarding international economic matters. Attached: Letter from Alexander P. Butterfield to Burns, 1971 Sept. 23.
        - 1971 Sept. 23 (Box 2)
          Outline of Phase II strategy of economic stabilization program, and 90-day freeze of wages and prices.
        - 1971 Oct. 7 (Box 2)
          Burns's notes on inflation speech.
        - 1971 Oct. 8 (Box 2)
          Attached: Biographical summary of Carl J. Thomsen.
        - 1971 Oct. 14 (Box 2)
          [Personal and Confidential] Burns's report to the President concerning his impressions of the IMF meeting.
        - 1971 Oct. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 1 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 5 (Box 2)
          Burns's notes on meeting with the president.
        - 1971 Nov. 8 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 13 (Box 2)
          Re: Burns's meeting with leaders of the New York financial community concerning the weakness of the stock market.
        - 1971 Nov. 16 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 17 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 18 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Nov. 24 (Box 2)
          Re: Nixon's inquiry about the money supply.
        - 1971 Dec. 6 (Box 2)
          Attached: Resolution adopted at Executive Session of the Conference of Chairmen and Deputy Chairmen of the Federal Reserve Banks, 1971 Dec. 2.
        - 1971 Dec. 15 (Box 2)
        - 1971 Dec. 21 (Box 2)
          Re: The figures on defense employment.
        - 1971 Dec. 22 (Box 2)
        - 1972 Feb. 3 (Box 3)
          Re: Nixon's concerns about the monetary policy. Burns assures him that the policy will promote economic expansion. Burns also states his doubts about estimated figures in the budget.
        - 1972 Feb. 4 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Feb. 9 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Feb. 25 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Apr. 17 (Box 3)
          Re: Burns's support of the President's decision to bomb North Vietnam
        - 1972 May 13 (Box 3)
        - 1972 June 5 (Box 3)
        - 1972 June 22 (Box 3)
          Re: Burns's evaluation of the Democrats' success in the recent polls and his suggestion to Nixon about what needs to be done.
        - 1972 June 24 (Box 3)
          Attached: Memorandum on Price Policy, 1972 June 24.
        - 1972 July 8 (Box 3)
        - 1972 July 12 (Box 3)
          Re: Burns's recent trip to Peru, Argentina, Brazil, and Venezuela. Burns addresses the economic and political situation in each country and comments on their economic and political relations with the US.
        - 1972 July 27 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Sept. 9 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Sept. 14 (Box 3)
          Re: Senate's failure to adopt the expenditure ceiling and its likely negative financial and monetary impacts.
        - 1972 Oct. 18 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Nov. 13 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Nov. 28 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Dec. 4 (Box 3)
          Re: Achievements of the Committee on Interest and Dividends
        - 1972 Dec. 7 (Box 3)
        - 1972 Dec. 28 (Box 3)
          Re: Concerns about the inflationary pressures in the next year
        - 1973 Jan. 24 (Box 3)
          Re: Nixon's achievement of enduring peace in Vietnam. Also points to the rebellious mood of Congress about excessive executive powers. Burns suggests that Nixon meet with prominent Congressmen and Senators more frequently.
        - 1973 Jan. 29 (Box 3)
          Re: Concerns regarding the Phase III of economic stabilization program. Attached: Report from the Division of Research and Statistic to Burns, Prospects for Inflation Under Phase III; a Preliminary Analysis, 1973 Jan. 23.
        - 1973 Feb. 1 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Feb. 8 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Feb. 20 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Mar. 6 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Mar. 8 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Mar. 30 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Apr. 2 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Apr. 13 (Box 3)
          Re: 45-day freeze of a broad range of prices.
        - 1973 Apr. 30 (Box 3)
          Re: Support for Nixon regarding the Watergate incident.
        - 1973 May 3 (Box 3)
          Re: Discontent of the Vice President.
        - 1973 May 7 (Box 3)
        - 1973 June 1 (Box 3)
          Re: Suggestions concerning fiscal, wage, and price policies
        - 1973 June 5 (Box 3)
        - 1973 June 9 (Box 3)
          Re: Restrictive fiscal devices to fight inflation.
        - 1973 June 27 (Box 3)
        - 1973 July 16 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Aug. 3 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Aug. 13 (Box 3)
          Re: Nixon's tone in his upcoming talk regarding Watergate and expression of doubt if his or any suggestions could work at the moment.
        - 1973 Sept. 10 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Sept. 12 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Oct. 16 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Dec. 5 (Box 3)
        - 1973 Dec. 6 (Box 3)
          Re: Gratitude to Nixon for appointing Burns Alternate Governor of the Monetary Fund.
        - 1974 Feb. 21 (Box 3)
        - 1974 Feb. 27 (Box 3)
        - 1974 Mar. 29 (Box 3)
          Re: Burns's visit to Russia.
        - 1974 Apr. 4 (Box 3)
        - 1974 May 1 (Box 3)
          Attached: 3 items. 2 copies of Burns's report to Nixon, Assistance to the Housing Industry, 1974 Apr. 30. Burns's report to Nixon, Public Service Employment Programs, 1974 May 1.
        - 1974 May 2 (Box 3)
          Statement by the President regarding combating inflation and price controls.
        - 1974 May 20 (Box 3)
        - 1974 May 28 (Box 3)
        - 1974 June 28 (Box 3)
          Re: Short-term deposits.
        - 1974 Aug. 7 (Box 3)
        - 1974 Aug. 13 (Box 3)
          Re: Nixon's address and farewell meeting.
        - 1974 Nov. 5 (Box 3)
        - 1983 Nov. 3 (Box 3)
        - 1985 June 24 (Box 3)
    - Ronald Wilson Reagan, 1980-1987, 2 folders
      Burns was U.S. Ambassador to Germany in the first Reagan administration; accordingly, some letters concern German-American relations. Most, however, are routine expressions of thanks or congratulations from President Reagan. Also included are briefly stated pieces of economic advice from Burns to Reagan.
      - From Reagan to Burns, 1980-1987, 19 letters
        Reagan's correspondence to Burns begins around the 1980 presidential election and accordingly includes many notes of thanks for support and economic advice during the campaign. Also included are Reagan's authorization of Burns as ambassador to Germany and notes on the federal deficit. Birthday wishes and congratulations upon receiving Jospeh Prize for Human Rights are also included.
        - 1980 July 30 (Box 3)
        - 1980 Sept. 19 (Box 3)
        - 1980 Sept. 22 (Box 3)
        - 1981 Feb. 6 (Box 3)
        - 1981 Feb. 14 (Box 3)
        - 1981 Mar. 13 (Box 3)
        - 1982 Jan. 4 (Box 3)
        - 1982 Jan. 12 (Box 3)
        - 1982 Jan. 29 (Box 3)
        - 1982 Apr. 19 (Box 3)
        - 1982 June 1 (Box 3)
        - 1983 Apr. 21 (Box 3)
        - 1984 Feb. 22 (Box 3)
        - 1984 Apr. 27 (Box 3)
        - 1984 Dec. 4 (Box 3)
        - 1985 Mar. 26 (Box 3)
        - 1986 June 23 (Box 3)
        - 1986 July 18 (Box 3)
        - 1987 May 8 (Box 3)
      - From Burns to Reagan, 1980-1985, 10 letters
        Burns's correspondence to Reagan consists mostly of congratulations and thanks. Of note, however, is Burns's 4-page confidential memo on the escalating tensions between the U.S. and the Federal Republic of Germany.
        - 1980 July 21 (Box 3)
          Re: Notice of policy statement to be issued by Burns's Committee to Fight Inflation
        - 1980 July 21 (Box 3)
          Re: Note of congratualtions upon Reagan's acceptance of the Republican nomination
        - 1980 Sept. 11 (Box 3)
        - 1980 Nov. 5 (Box 3)
        - 1981 Feb. 10 (Box 3)
        - 1981 Aug. 31 (Box 3)
          Confidential: Discussion of the "accumulating tensions" between the U.S. and the FRG
        - 1984 May 8 (Box 3)
        - 1985 Apr. 16 (Box 3)
        - 1985 May 10 (Box 3)
    - Donald Regan, 1985-1987, 2 letters
      Regan's letters to Burns are routine notes of thanks for support.
      - 1985 Apr. 4 (Box 3)
      - 1987 Mar. 10 (Box 3)
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1964-1977, 3 letters
      Rockefeller's letters to Burns are routine notes of thanks for friendship and sending materials.
      - 1964 Jan. 11 (Box 3)
      - 1967 Dec. 13 (Box 3)
      - 1977 Feb. 24 (Box 3)
    - Helmut Schmidt, 1982-1985, 8 letters
      Schmidt's letters to Burns are routine notes of thanks and support for cordial German-American relations.
      - 1982 Jan. 8 (Box 3)
        Written in German.
      - 1982 Mar. 5 (Box 3)
      - 1982 Oct. 6 (Box 3)
      - 1983 July 17 (Box 3)
      - 1983 Sept. 8 (Box 3)
      - 1983 Oct. 16 (Box 3)
      - 1984 Jan. (Box 3)
      - 1985 Jan. 17 (Box 3)
    - George P. Schultz, 1982-1986, 10 letters
      Schultz's letters to Burns are routine notes of thanks for friendship and sending materials.
      - 1982 May 18 (Box 3)
      - 1982 Nov. 8 (Box 3)
      - 1982 Dec. 8 (Box 3)
      - 1983 Nov. 24 (Box 3)
      - 1984 Apr. 18 (Box 3)
      - 1985 May 6 (Box 3)
      - 1985 June 10 (Box 3)
      - 1985 Aug. 7 (Box 3)
      - 1985 Oct. 28 (Box 3)
      - 1986 June 17 (Box 3)
    - George Stigler, undated, 3 letters (Box 3)
      Stigler's letters to Burns discuss academic posts, other economists, Milton Friedman, and personal matters.
    - Margaret Thatcher, 1985 and undated, 3 letters
      Thatcher's letters to Burns are routine notes of thanks for friendship and sending materials.
      - 1985 Feb. 27 (Box 3)
      - 1985 May 21 (Box 3)
      - undated (Box 3)
    - Caspar Weinberger, 1981-1985, 7 letters
      Weinberger's letters to Burns discuss the exports of military and electronic goods to the Soviet bloc and Reagan's Strategic Defensive Initiative. Also included are notes of thanks for sending materials and for successfully intervening with German-American trade relations.
      - 1981 Dec. 21 (Box 3)
      - 1982 Jan. 18 (Box 3)
      - 1982 July 6 (Box 3)
      - 1983 Apr. 18 (Box 3)
      - 1983 Nov. 23 (Box 3)
      - 1984 May 14 (Box 3)
      - 1985 Jan. 11 (Box 3)
    - Other Individuals, 1940-1985 and undated, 3 folders
      Correspondents include Bob Dole, Warren Berger, and Barbara Walters.
      - To Burns, 1940-1987 and undated, 30 letters
        - 1940 Jan. 28 (Box 3)
          From Dan Creamer.
        - 1943 May 24 (Box 3)
          From Eduardo Hornedo.
        - 1956 Nov. 26 (Box 3)
          From Jacob K. Javits.
        - 1975 Sept. 25 (Box 3)
          From Elizabeth MacDonald Manning. Attached memorandum: Proposal for the Establishment of a Consultative Body in the Communications Area.
        - 1976 Sept. 21 (Box 3)
          From Bob Dole regarding his nomination as the presidential candidate.
        - 1977 Apr. 2 (Box 3)
          From David Eisenhower.
        - 1978 May 12 (Box 3)
          From Bert Lance.
        - 1980 Mar. 16 (Box 3)
          From Warren Berger.
        - 1981 Sept. 28 (Box 3)
          From Frederick J. Kroesen, Jr. to Burns.
        - 1981 Dec. 4 (Box 3)
          From Sam Nunn. Attached article: Arms Control: What We Should Do
        - 1982 Jan. 19 (Box 3)
          From Pjotr Abrassimow to Burns. Written in German
        - 1982 Apr. 21 (Box 3)
          From Charles W. Colson to Burns.
        - 1982 Apr. 21 (Box 3)
          From Theodore Hesburgh to Burns.
        - 1982 June 16 (Box 3)
          From Jeanne J. Kirkpatrick to Burns.
        - 1983 Feb. 24 (Box 3)
          From Walter J. Stoessel, Jr. to Burns.
        - 1983 Apr. 7 (Box 3)
          From Barbara Walters to Burns.
        - 1983 Oct. 25 (Box 3)
          From Karl Carstens to Burns. Written in German.
        - 1983 Nov. 23 (Box 3)
          From Malcolm Baldridge to Burns.
        - 1983 (Box 3)
          Writer unknown. Written in Russian
        - 1984 July 8 (Box 3)
          From Berndt von Staden to Burns.
        - 1984 Nov. 3 (Box 3)
          From Otto Graf Lambsdorff to Burns.
        - 1985 Apr. 12 (Box 3)
          From John J. McCloy to Burns.
        - 1985 May 28 (Box 3)
          From Kenneth W. Dam to Burns.
        - 1985 July 12 (Box 3)
          From Jacob K. Javits to Burns. Attached article: Senate Resolutions 197: Resolution to agree to cooperate with the Jacob K. Javits Senate Fellowship Program
        - 1986 July 2 (Box 3)
          From Raymond Barre to Burns.
        - 1986 Aug. 8 (Box 3)
          From Richard V. Allen to Burns.
        - 1986 Aug. 26 (Box 3)
          From Charles McC. Mathias, Jr. to Burns.
        - 1986 Sept. 9 (Box 3)
          From Samuel R. Pierce, Jr. to Burns.
        - 1987 Jan. 12 (Box 3)
          From Gunther van Well to Burns.
        - 1987 Mar. 13 (Box 3)
          From Howard H. Baker, Jr. to Burns.
        - Undated (Box 3)
          From Raymond Barre, President of France. Attached: English translation letter
      - From Burns, 1955-1985, 4 letters
        - 1955 July 18 (Box 3)
          To Reuven Shiloah in the Israeli Embassy.
        - 1976 May 4 (Box 3)
          To Elliot Nathan Stone.
        - 1985 Apr. 16 (Box 3)
          To Jack Velcoff. Attached: Letter from Jack Velcoff to Burns, 1985 Mar 12
        - 1985 Oct. 31 (Box 3)
          To Doug Coe. Attached: Letter from Coe to Burns, 1985 Dec. 9.
  - Correspondence by Topic, 1926-1981, 9 folders
    Mostly dating from Burns' early career as an economist, this subseries contains Burns' correspondence with other economists, university administrators, the Republican Party, and private sector businesses. Arranged alphabetically by topic and then chronologically within.
    - Academic career, 1928-1956, bulk 1928-1930 (Box 3)